one of the exciting things about a large
一个大的令人兴奋的事情之一
language model is you could use it to build
你可以用它来建立语言模型
a custom chat bot with only a modest amount of effort
一个自定义聊天机器人，只需要少量的努力
chat GPT the web interface is a way for you to have a
聊天GPT的web界面是一种方式，你有一个
conversational interface a conversation
会话接口会话
via a large language model
通过一个大的语言模型
but one of the cool things is you can also
但很酷的一件事是你也可以
use a large language model to build
使用大型语言模型进行构建
your custom chatbot to maybe
你的自定义聊天机器人也许
play the role of an AI customer service agent or an AI
扮演人工智能客户服务代理或人工智能的角色
order taker for a restaurant
餐馆的点菜员
and in this video you learn how to do that for yourself
在这个视频中，你将学习如何为自己做到这一点
I'm going to describe the components of the Openai Chat
我将描述Openai Chat的组件
completions format in more detail
完成格式更详细
and then you're going to build a chatbot yourself
然后你要自己造一个聊天机器人
so let's get into it
让我们开始吧
so first
首先
we'll set up the Openai Python package as usual
我们将像往常一样设置Openai Python包
so chat models like Chat GBT
所以像chat GBT这样的聊天模式
are actually
实际上是
trained to take a series of messages as input
训练接受一系列的信息作为输入
and return a model generated message as output
并返回模型生成的消息作为输出
and so although the chat
所以尽管聊天
format is designed to make multi turn conversations
格式的设计，使多回合的对话
like this easy
就像这样简单
we've kind of seen through the previous videos that
在之前的视频中我们已经知道了
it's also just as useful for
它也同样有用
single turn tasks without any conversation
没有任何对话的单回合任务
and so next we're going to define two helper functions
接下来我们要定义两个辅助函数
so this is the one that we've been using
这是我们一直在用的
throughout all the videos
在所有的视频中
and it's the gat completion function
它是gat补全函数
but if you kind of look at it
但是如果你仔细看
we give a prompt but then
我们给一个提示，但是
inside the function what we're actually doing
在函数内部我们实际在做什么
is putting this prompt into
把这个提示放入
what looks like some kind of user message
看起来像是某种用户消息
and this is because the chat GBT
这是因为这个话题是同性恋
model is a chat model
模型是一个聊天模型
which means it's
也就是说
trained to take a series of messages as input
训练接受一系列的信息作为输入
and then return a model generated messages output
然后返回模型生成的消息输出
so the user message is
用户消息是
the input and then the assistant messages
输入，然后是助理信息
the output
输出
so in this video
在这个视频中
we're going to actually use a different
我们要用一个不同的
helper function
helper函数
and instead of kind of
而不是
putting a single prompt as input and getting a
将单个提示符作为输入，并获得
single completion
单完成
we're going to
我们要
pass in a list of messages and these messages can be
传入消息列表，这些消息可以
kind of from a variety of different roles
从各种不同的角色
so I'll describe those
我来描述一下
so here's an example of a list of messages
这里有一个消息列表的例子
and so the first
所以第一个
message is a system message
Message是系统消息
which kind of gives an overall instruction
哪一种给出了全面的指导
and then after this message we have
在这条信息之后，我们有
turns between the user and the assistant
在用户和助手之间切换
and this will kind of continue to go on
这还会继续下去
and if you've ever used ChatGPT
如果你曾经使用过ChatGPT
the web interface then
然后是网络界面
your messages are the user messages
您的消息是用户消息
and then ChatGPT's messages are the assistant messages
然后ChatGPT的消息是助理消息
so the system message
所以系统信息
helps to kind of set the behavior and persona
有助于设定行为和角色
of the assistant
助理的
and it
而且它
acts as kind of a high level instruction for the
作为一种高级指令
conversation so you can kind
交谈让你可以亲切
of think of it as whispering in the assistant's ear
把它想象成在助理耳边低语
and kind of guiding its responses
并引导它的反应
without the user being aware of the system message
在用户不知道系统消息的情况下
so as the user
所以作为用户
if you've ever used Chart GBT
如果你用过Chart GBT
you probably don't know what's in Chart GBT
你可能不知道图表GBT是什么
system message
系统消息
the benefit of the system message is that it provides
系统消息的好处是它提供了
you the developer
你是开发者
with a way to kind of frame the conversation
用一种框定对话的方式
without making
不作
the request itself part of the conversation
请求本身是对话的一部分
so you can kind of
所以你可以
guide the assistant and kind of whisper in its ear
引导助手，在它耳边低语
and guide its responses without making the user aware
并在不让用户意识到的情况下引导其响应
so
所以
now let's try to use these messages in a conversation
现在让我们试着在对话中使用这些信息
so we'll use our new helper function
我们将使用新的辅助函数
to get the completion from the messages
从消息中获得完成
and we are also using a higher temperature
我们也使用了更高的温度
so the system message says
系统消息说
you are an assistant that speaks like Shakespeare
你是个说话像莎士比亚的助理
so this is us kind of
这是我们
describing to the assistant how it should behave
向助理描述它应该怎么做
and then the first user messages tell me a joke
然后第一个用户消息告诉我一个笑话
the next is why did the chicken cross the road
下一个问题是为什么鸡要过马路
and then the final user message is I don't know
最后的用户留言是我不知道
so if we run this
如果我们运行这个
the response is to get to the other side
我们的反应是去另一边
let's try again
我们再试一次
to get to the other side
去到另一边
Fasaro Madame Tis an olden classic that never fails
《法萨罗夫人》是一部永远不会失败的经典名著
so there's our shakespearean response
这就是我们的莎士比亚式反应
and let's actually try one more thing
我们再来试一件事
because I want to make it even clearer
因为我想让它更清晰
that this is the assistant message
这是助理留言
so here let's just go and print
我们来打印一下
the entire message response
整个消息响应
so just to make this even clearer this
为了更清楚一点
response is an assistant message
回复是一条辅助消息
so the role is assistant
所以这个角色是助理
and then the content is the message itself
然后内容就是信息本身
so that's what's happening in this helper function
这就是辅助函数的作用
we're just kind of
我们只是有点
passing out the content of the message
传递消息的内容
so now let's do another example
现在我们再做一个例子
so here our messages are
这就是我们的信息
this is the message is your friendly chatbot
这是你的友好聊天机器人的消息
and the first user message is hi my name is ISA
第一条用户信息是嗨，我的名字是ISA
and we want to
我们想要
get the first user message
获取第一条用户消息
so let's execute this for the first assistant message
让我们对第一条助理消息执行这个
and so the first message is hello ESA
第一个信息是你好，ESA
it's nice to meet you
很高兴认识你
how can I assist you today
今天我能为您做些什么
now let's try another example
现在我们来试试另一个例子
so here our messages are
这就是我们的信息
system message your friendly chatbot
系统消息您的友好聊天机器人
and the first user messages
第一个用户消息
yes
是的
can you remind me what is my name
你能提醒我一下我叫什么名字吗
and let's get the response
让我们得到响应
and as you can see
如你所见
the model doesn't actually know my name
模特其实不知道我的名字
so each conversation with
所以每次和
a language model is a standalone interaction
语言模型是一个独立的交互
which means that you must provide
这意味着你必须提供
all relevant messages
所有相关信息
for the model to draw from in the current conversation
用于在当前对话中吸取的模型
if you want the model to draw from or
如果你想让模型从或
remember earlier parts of a conversation
记住之前的对话
you must provide the
您必须提供
earlier exchanges in the input to the model
模型输入的早期交换
and so we'll refer to this as context
所以我们把它称为上下文
so let's try this
我们来试一下
so now we've kind of given
现在我们已经给出了
the context that the model needs
模型需要的上下文
which is my name
这是我的名字
in the previous messages we'll ask the same question
在前面的信息中，我们会问同样的问题
so we'll ask what my name is
所以我们会问我叫什么
and the model is able to respond because it has
这个模型能够做出反应是因为它有
all of the context it needs
它需要的所有上下文
in this kind of list of messages that we input to it
在我们输入的消息列表中
so now you're going to build your own chat bot
现在您将构建自己的聊天机器人
this chat bot is going to be called auto bot
这个聊天机器人将被称为auto bot
and
和
we're going to automate the collection of user prompts
我们将自动收集用户提示
and assistant responses
以及助手的回应
in order to build
为了建立
this order bot
这个订单
and it's going to take orders at a pizza restaurant
它将在一家披萨店接受订单
so first we're going to define this helper function
首先我们要定义这个辅助函数
and what this is doing is it's going to
它所做的就是
kind of collect our user messages
收集用户信息
so we can avoid typing them in by hand in the same
这样我们就可以避免手工输入了
in the way that we did above
用我们上面做的方法
and this is going to kind of collect
这是一种收集
prompts from a user interface that will build below
将在下面构建的用户界面提示
and then append it to a list called context
然后将它附加到一个名为context的列表
and then it will call the model with that context every
然后它会用那个context调用模型
time and the Rodal response is then
时间和罗达尔反应是
also added to the context
还添加到上下文中
so the kind of model message
这是一种模型信息
is added to the context
添加到上下文中
the user message is added to the context so on
用户消息被添加到上下文中，以此类推
so it just kind of grows longer and longer
所以它会越来越长
this way the model has the information
这样模型就有了信息
it needs to determine what to do next
它需要决定下一步该做什么
and so now we'll set up and run
现在我们设置并运行
this kind of UI to display the audibot
这种UI来显示audibot
and so here's the context
这就是背景
and it contains the system message
它包含系统消息
that contains the menu
包含了菜单
and
和
note that every time we call the language model
请注意，每次调用语言模型时
we're going to use the same context and
我们将使用相同的上下文
the context is building up over time
随着时间的推移，环境正在逐渐形成
and then let's execute this
然后我们来执行这个
okay I'm going to say hi
好的，我要打个招呼
I would like to order a pizza
我想订一份披萨
and the assistant says great
店员说很好
what pizza would you like to order
你想点什么披萨
we have pepperoni cheese and eggplant pizza
我们有意大利辣香肠奶酪和茄子披萨
hmm
hmm
how much are they
多少钱?
great okay we have the prices
好的，我们有价格了
I think I'm feeling a medium eggplant pizza
我想我想吃中号茄子披萨
so
所以
as you can imagine we could continue this conversation
你可以想象我们可以继续这个话题
and let's kind of look at what we've put in the system
让我们看看我们在系统中加入了什么
message
消息
so you are order bought
所以你被订购了
an automated service to collect
自动收款服务
orders for a pizza restaurant
比萨店的订单
you first greet the customer
你首先问候顾客
then collect the order
然后收集订单
and then ask if it's a pickup or delivery
然后问是取货还是送货
you wait to collect the entire order
你等着收整笔订单
then summarize it and check for a final
然后总结并检查期末考试
time if the customer wants to add anything else
如果客户想添加其他内容，则需要时间
if it's a delivery you can ask for an address
如果是快递，你可以询问地址
finally you collect the payment
最后你收到了付款
make sure to clarify all options
一定要明确所有的选项
extras and sizes to uniquely identify the item
额外的和尺寸，以唯一地识别项目
from the menu
从菜单中
you respond in a short
你的回答很简短
very conversational friendly style
非常友好的谈话风格
the menu includes and then here we have the menu
菜单包括，这里是菜单
so let's go back to our conversation
让我们回到刚才的话题
and let's see if the assistant kind of
让我们看看助理是否
has been following the instructions
一直按照指示做吗
okay great the assistant asks
`好的，太好了，`助理问道
if we want any toppings
如果我们想要配料的话
which we kind of specified in the system message
是我们在系统消息中指定的吗
so I think we want no extra toppings
所以我想我们不需要额外的配料
sure thing is there anything else we'd like to order
当然，我们还需要点别的东西吗
mmm
mmm
let's get some water actually
我们喝点水吧
fries
薯条
small or large
小或大
and this is great because we kind of
这很棒，因为我们有点
ask the assistant in the system message to kind of
请系统里的助手留言给种
clarify extras and sides
澄清额外费用和附加费用
so
所以
and so you get the idea
这样你就明白了
and please feel free to play with this yourself
你可以自己玩这个
you can pause the video
你可以暂停视频
and just go ahead and run this
然后继续运行这个
in your own notebook on the left
在你左边的笔记本上
and so
所以
now we can ask the model to create a JSON summary
现在我们可以要求模型创建一个JSON摘要
that we could send to the order system
我们可以把它发送到订购系统
based on the conversation
根据对话
so we're now appending another system message
所以我们现在附加另一个系统消息
which is an instruction
这是一个指令
and we're saying create a JSON summary of the previous
我们说的是创建一个JSON摘要
food order
食物订单
itemize the price for each item
列出每件商品的价格
the field should be 1 pizza include side
场地面积应为1个披萨，包括配料
2 list of toppings 3 list of drinks and 4 list of sides
2份配料清单3份饮料清单4份配菜清单
and finally the total price
最后是总价格
and you could also
你也可以
use a user message here
在这里使用用户消息
this does not have to be a system message
这并不一定是一个系统消息
so let's execute this
我们来执行这个
and notice in this case we're using a lower temperature
注意，在这个例子中，我们用的是较低的温度
because for these kinds of tasks
因为对于这类任务
we want the output to be fairly predictable
我们希望输出是相当可预测的
for a conversational agent
对于会话代理
you might want to use a higher temperature
你可能需要用更高的温度
however in this case
然而在这种情况下
I would maybe use a lower temperature as well
我可能也会用更低的温度
because for a customer assistant
因为对于一个客户助理来说
chart but you might want the output to be
图表，但您可能希望输出为
to be a bit more predictable as well
也更容易被预测
and so here we have the summary of our order
这是顺序的总结
and so we could submit this to the
所以我们可以把这个提交给
order system if we wanted to
如果我们想的话，可以对系统进行排序
so there we have it
所以我们得到了它
you've built your variage order chatbot
您已经构建了您的可变订单聊天机器人
feel free to
请随意
kind of customize it yourself and play around
你可以自己定制，自己玩
with the system message
带有系统消息
to change the behavior
改变行为
of the chatbot and kind of
聊天机器人之类的
get it to act as different personas
让它扮演不同的角色
with different knowledge
拥有不同的知识